=Royal Upstart 2=
(Based on "Zhenguan Foolish Son-in-Law")
=Episode 1=
(Selling Hotpot in Ancient Times)
Four people drink
four buckets of water in four days.
Then, how many buckets
do eight people drink in eight days?
One person drinks one bucket a day.
So eight people should
drink eight buckets in eight days.
Wrong!
(Wei Hao)
You don't know the multiplication table,
(Modern Science Talent)
so if we're talking about arithmetic,
(Ancient Fool)
in the entire Great Yong Dynasty,
no one can outcalculate me!
A fool
dares to be so arrogant
in front of us scholars?
Aren't you just a fool
who only knows how to fight?
Keep babbling,
and I'll beat you up!
How dare you
(Talent Recruitment Fair)
be so insolent at the Princess's recruitment fair!
Why is this person so foolish?
Your Highness,
he is just a fool from the West City.
(Wei Ning'an, Eldest Princess
of the Great Yong Dynasty)
(A fool?)
(She's so beautiful.)
(No wonder my original self liked her.)
Wei Hao,
if you want to win
first place at the Princess's fair,
you must first pass
my test.
Stop talking.
Give me the problem.
(Duan Lun, Minister of Works
of the Great Yong Dynasty)
Fine.
Listen carefully.
A thief
travels one li every quarter hour.
A constable pursues him an hour later,
traveling three li every quarter hour.
When will he catch up?
This problem
took me a long time to study...
He catches up in two quarters hour.
Don't keep interrupting me.
(Solved: Two quarters hour)
Wei the Fool got it right.
You...
Sir.
How...
How is it possible?
Such a complex problem,
how could it be solved
in less than a day?
Are you convinced?
I am not.
Wei Hao, you brat.
Do you dare to take
another problem from me?
No time.
You...
I came here today for the Princess.
You have already delayed
my serious business,
you know?
I...
Wei the Fool,
don't be so arrogant.
Even if you beat everyone here,
you shouldn't make
the boastful claim that no one
in Great Yong can outcalculate you.
Girl,
I didn't lie to you.
If you don't believe me,
you can call all the scholars
of the Great Yong Dynasty,
including all those officials,
to come and compete
with me in arithmetic.
But
if they all lose,
you have to marry me.
You rogue.
Do you believe I'll...
Don't call me a rogue all the time.
Let me tell you...
Although I'm called the "Fool",
I'm not stupid.
Don't listen to the rumors outside.
If you follow me,
I won't let you down.
You...
Then, it's a deal.
Tomorrow at Juxian Restaurant,
I'll be open to challenges.
Girl, you...
If you dare call me "Girl" again.
You bring everyone you know
who knows arithmetic.
It's a deal.
If they all lose to me,
you marry me.
You...
Wei the Fool,
you just wait.
(Since I, a genius in the sciences,)
(have traveled back in time
into this ancient fool,)
(I shall help him fulfill
his wish of marrying the princess.)
(But to be honest,)
(as for this princess,)
(I fell for her at first sight, too.)
Accessories.
(Talent Recruitment Hall)
Little accessories.
Young Master.
Young Master,
you really are here.
Mister Wang, are you here
for the recruitment too?
No, something happened at home.
(Mister Wang, the Wei family steward)
Young Madam wants you to come back now.
She's always overreacting.
What could possibly happen?
Mister Wang,
you're not taking me home.
Why did you bring me here?
That's because we...
Wei Hao.
Wei Cong?
Your family can no longer afford
(Wei Cong, a Wei, Wei Hao's cousin)
to fund our clansmen from all over
who came to the capital for the exams.
To the clan,
you no longer have any value.
So,
you're not qualified to live in
the Wei Mansion anymore.
You only deserve to live
in this remote and messy courtyard.
Keep pretending.
Let me beat you to death.
Young Master,
why are you getting violent again?
They're insulting us at our doorstep.
Am I usually this cowardly?
Just you wait.
I'm hitting you.
I'll beat you to death.
Where's my younger aunt?
She's inside.
Young Master.
Aunt.
(Lin Luo, sworn sister of Wei's mother)
Hao,
you're finally back.
They are being such bullies.
Who do they think they are?
I'm going to find them.
Where are you going?
Are you going to fight again?
Our family doesn't have
money for settlements anymore.
Where did you hide my 600 guan of cash?
Give it to me quickly.
If I hand it to the clan,
we can move back to
the Wei ancestral home.
I used the money
to buy a restaurant.
In two months,
I'll pay you back with interest.
You spendthrift.
(Juxian Restaurant)
Move a bit faster.
Alright.
Young Master, the copper pots from
the blacksmith are all set.
I don't understand.
Why is this copper pot
called a "hotpot"?
Waiter.
Come here.
Buy a thousand portions
based on this recipe.
How much will it cost?
Boss,
a thousand portions will cost five guan.
Five guan?
Is that a lot?
Boss,
let me put it this way.
My monthly wage is only ten wen.
To earn one guan,
I'd have to work for ten months.
(One wen is like
one yuan in the modern world,)
(so one guan would be a hundred yuan.)
Young Master,
five guan really is a lot.
If we can't afford it, let's get less.
Young Madam...
Don't worry.
After today,
hotpot will be a hit
all over the capital.
When that time comes,
I'll pay my aunt back a thousandfold.
A hit?
We don't even have a single customer.
How can it be a hit?
Is Wei Hao here?
Isn't that a customer?
Customer?
What are you all waiting for?
Go welcome them.
- Right...
Greetings, sirs.
Please come in, sirs.
Please.
So, you are Wei the Fool?
Who are you calling a fool?
Do I even know you?
Wei Hao.
Was it you who spoke so arrogantly
at the recruitment fair?
(Dai Zou, Minister of Revenue of the Great Yong)
You claimed your arithmetic skills
were unmatched in
the entire Great Yong Dynasty.
So, you're the people the Princess sent?
Today,
I have brought the officials
from the Ministry of Revenue
to test your mettle.
The food is ready.
This...
What is this?
It smells good.
The scent makes my mouth water.
This aroma is divine.
What is this thing?
The smell alone is making me salivate.
The broth is boiling and fragrant.
It's refreshing.
This is the new dish
launched by Juxian Restaurant,
a hotpot.
Hotpot?
I have never seen this before.
However,
it certainly smells exquisite.
Indeed.
I wonder if we might have a taste?
If you want to compete, then compete.
Don't stand around here
blocking my business.
Fine.
Wei Hao, here's the question.
Not so fast.
From now on,
if you want to challenge me
in arithmetic,
you must bet one guan per question.
One guan?
(Zhangsun Chong, Vice Minister of
Revenue of the Great Yong Dynasty)
Wei the Fool,
what if you can't answer
within 15 minutes?
Then, I will
pay out tenfold.
I'll give you ten guan.
Oh, my young master.
With so many people,
paying ten guan to each...
This is...
Bring it on.
I'll go first.
Suppose there is a rope one chi long.
If it is formed into a circle,
what is its vertical length?
Can you answer that?
This...
How can we calculate this
without a ruler,
Young Master?
(c = 1 chi)
Isn't this just finding the diameter from the circumference?
(d = c/π)
One chi divided by
(d = 1/3.1415926)
3.1415926.
Absolute nonsense.
What is the
"3.1415926"
you are talking about?
You...
What's wrong?
That was written by Zu Chongzhi.
It has existed for many years.
(d ≈ 0.3183, 1 chi ≈ 3.18 cun)
The vertical length is three cun, one fen, and eight li.
How...
How did you calculate so quickly?
It took my chief registrars
several days to come up with
three cun and two fen.
But you were even accurate to eight li.
I told you,
I'm the world's No. 1 in arithmetic.
Next.
Me.
He's way too arrogant.
Stump him.
I'll go next.
I don't believe you can solve this.
The wood needed to build the bridge is
3,500 pieces.
Next.
This is my question.
The length of the water tank is
three chi and eighty-seven fen.
Next.
The raw meat must be three
wen cheaper to break even.
Next.
Young Master.
I... This...
Look at this...
Young Master.
Sirs, those who have lost
can have a free
hotpot meal at this restaurant.
Well...
I've been enduring
this delicious smell for a long time.
I lost one guan.
Come on.
Let's eat it back.
Those who lost a lot
can go to the private rooms upstairs.
I lost three questions.
Three guan.
And me.
I lost three guan too.
Go, go.
Alright.
Have a seat anywhere.
Anyway, we can make up
for the loss by eating.
Go on, gentlemen.
The fatty beef is like
snow melting on the lips,
and tripe gently caresses the throat.
Such a delicacy on earth.
It tastes even better than it smells.
Wei...
Wei Hao,
I should be the one
to ask the final question.
But I'm hungry.
Can I have a taste first?
No.
(Do they really think
I have nothing better to do)
(than to find them
to compete in arithmetic?)
(After today, my Juxian Restaurant will
surely become famous in the capital)
(and become the most
expensive restaurant.)
(This marketing was a success.)
He really is a fool?
It's true.
I didn't believe it at first either,
but everyone in West City says so.
This Wei Hao
fights in the streets all day.
It feels like
(Chan, Eldest Princess's personal maid)
he's missing a screw.
He's very impulsive.
No wonder he behaves so recklessly.
Turns out there's
something wrong with his head.
His family used to be
the richest in West City.
His parents went to Bashu,
so he's being raised
by her younger aunt now.
Well, no wonder then.
The only son of the family
and the only heir in five generations.
I wonder
how those court officials
are doing with their bets.
Is it Juxian Restaurant?
Let's go.
Let's go see him make a fool of himself.
♪Everyone says I'm a big silly fool♪
♪When things happen,
I only know how to count on my fingers♪
♪They shake their heads
and say I'm pitiful♪
♪Sigh and walk away♪
♪Little do they know,
I am sharp and bright♪
♪With a heart like a mirror,
I understand the world's♪
♪Colors and darkness♪
♪But I keep my edge hidden♪
♪The day I become famous
is just around the corner♪
♪In the hotpot restaurant,
skewers boil in the broth♪
♪People come and go,
with few worries or troubles♪
♪The clacking of the abacus rings out♪
♪See me differently.
Who dares to challenge me?♪
♪The world mistakes me♪
♪For an ignorant and stubborn fool♪
♪As the storm approaches♪
♪I just shrug and watch with a smile♪
♪This foolish image is convenient♪
♪I use it as a protective shield♪
♪Navigating with ease, I attract♪
♪A lucky star to accompany me♪
♪In a peaceful golden age♪
♪I hold my lady's hand
to watch the world♪
♪Pouring youth and fireworks♪
♪Into a precious glazed cup♪
♪Having experienced life's changes♪
♪And tasted its highs and lows♪
♪My wish has finally come true♪
♪To stay by your side♪
♪In this fleeting world♪
♪We are free and happy♪
♪From a nobody♪
♪To someone now famous♪
♪Ordinary people laugh at me♪
♪But I laugh at how they
cannot see through it all♪
♪Let others plot and scheme♪
♪I will keep my heart unchanged♪
♪In this vast world♪
♪I find my own leisurely freedom♪
♪The world is bustling,
and things constantly change♪
♪Everything ends eventually♪
♪All that remains before my eyes♪
♪Is this street wandering,
still tinged with pity♪
♪No matter how time flies♪
♪Even if the falling snow♪
♪Dyes the hair at our temples white♪
♪All I want now♪
♪Is to pray for
my lady's peace and safety♪
♪Year after year♪